So we have created shots,
我们制作好了子弹
and we can now shoot them.
并且子弹可以发射出去
But we have a problem.
但是这里存在一个问题
Our shots are simply accumulating in the scene
我们飞向Z轴无穷远处的子弹
flying off towards infinity on the Z axis.
将会逐渐积累起来
Even though each shot only requires a
虽然每发子弹所需要的系统资源
tiny amount of our resource budget
非常小,如果这些子弹逐渐
we will quickly have a lot of them,
积累起来,每次计算这些子弹的飞行和
each being processed and moved and tested in our scene.
检测它们的碰撞将耗费大量的系统资源
We need to find a way to remove these shots
因此我们应该在这些子弹飞出视野的时候
from the scene when they leave the game area.
将他们从游戏中剔除出去
There are a number of different ways that
实现这个功能有很多种
that we can approach this issue.
不同的方法
In this assignment we are going to create
本章节中我们会围绕游戏视野
a box around our game
建立一个盒子作为边界
and we will destroy these shots as they
如果有子弹离开盒子
leave the box.
我们将这个子弹销毁
As an added bonus this boundary box
这个边际盒子
will also deal with our hazards and
还可以用来销毁
destroy them when they leave the game area as well.
离开游戏场景的小行星
To create a box around our game area
为了建立这个覆盖了整个游戏场景的盒子
create a new cube by using
我们先点选Create menu 选择Cube
the Create menu and selecting Cube.
来新建一个立方体
Now a cube has a mesh
这个新建的立方体自带了
held by the mesh filter, and a mesh renderer
网格过滤器和网格渲染器
that we don't strictly need for our purposes.
这些对于我们的目的来说都是多余的
We only need a box collider component.
我们只需要碰撞检测机这一个组件
However, being able to see the cube rendered
但是，如果可以看到这个边际盒子的话
in the game view will be helpful to us
在调整这个盒子大小使其适应游戏边界区域时
when placing the box around our game area.
我们的操作会方便很多
So we'll use a cube
所以我们保留
with it's mesh, mesh renderer and box collider
这个四边形边界的
for our bounding box.
网格,网格渲染和碰撞检测机组件
Rename the cube Boundary.
将这个四边形重命名为Boundary.
And reset it's transform to make sure
重置一下变形组件
it is at origin.
确保四边形在原点位置
If we turn the mesh renderer off
如果我们把网格渲染器关闭
we will see the box collider in the scene
我们将看到这个盒子的碰撞检测器
We don't want a physical collision with this box.
我们不需要知道这个立方体发生的物理碰撞
We want this box to trigger a new action
我们只需要当一个对象离开这个盒子的时候
when our object's leave this box.
触发某个事件
We want this box to be a trigger collider.
我们希望这个盒子是一个碰撞检测的触发器
So on the box collider component select
所以在碰撞检测器的组建中点选
Is Trigger.
Is Trigger
Now in our Game view we can't
现在我们观察下游戏视图
see our boundary.
我们看不到边界
the gizmo indicating the box collider
小图标已经暗示了这个盒子形状的碰撞检测机
is only visible in the Scene view.
只能在场景视图中可见
The trigger collider by itself is invisible
因为碰撞触发器对我们的游戏视角相机
to our game camera.
来说并不可见
This makes sense though, we don't want to see
这样很合理,我们并不想在游戏中
see our triggers in the game.
看到这个触发器
This is why using a cube makes sense.
这就是我们选择cube作为触发器的原因
Let's turn the mesh renderer back on.
让我们把网格渲染重新打开
We want to place this box evenly
我们需要把这个盒子套在
around the game area.
整个游戏区域上
The centre of the game area is defined by
游戏区域的中心位置
the position of the camera as it looks
是由相机的位置决定的
down on the game.
相机的正下方就是中心位置
The camera's transform on the X/Z plane
相机的在X/Z平面的位移参数是
is 0,5.
0,5
So let's keep the boundary's transform position
我们把boundary的位移参数
X at 0 and let's set the boundary's
根据相机的位置也设定一下
transform position Z to 5.
X设定为0，Z设定为5
Next, using the transform scale
下一步我们要调整边界盒子的
let's change the scale of the cube
大小,我们调整Scale参数的值
until it surrounds our scene.
使其环绕在我们的场景周围
We are less concerned by the sides for this
我们不太关心两边的情况
particular game, as nothing will leave
因为在我们目前的游戏中
the game area by the sides of our game.
并不会有对象从两边飞出我们的视野
Our background is 15 units wide
我们的背景是15个单位宽
so let's match that with our cube
我们就按照这个值来设定我们的cube
and use a value of 15 in the
X方向的比例值
transform scale X.
设定为15
The top and bottom are more critical.
上下的边界要求的更严格一些
We want to get the boundary as close
我们希望boundary可以跟我们
to the edge of the game area as possible
游戏区域的边界靠的足够近
as all of our shots and hazards
因为我们的子弹会从上方边界离开
will leave the game area by the top
小行星则会从
or bottom edge.
下方边界离开
This looks like about 20.
这个值大约在20左右
So let's use a value of 20 for the
我们就把Z方向的scale
transform scale Z.
值设定为20
We actually know that 20 is the
其实我们是知道20
correct value because 20 is twice
是这个正确值
the size of our orthographic camera.
因为20刚好是我们正交相继尺寸的2倍
The number of units from the top of the screen
正交相机屏幕的顶端单位值
to the bottom is always twice the value of
也正好是正交相机的底端单位值
of our camera's orthographic size.
的2倍
Now that we have placed the boundary
我们现在已经设置好了边际
we can turn off the mesh renderer.
我们可以把网格渲染关掉
When we look in the Scene view we can now see
在场景视图中,我们仍然可以看到绿色的
our collider in green surrounding our game area.
环绕我们场景的碰撞检测机边界
We now need to have our boundary do something.
现在让我们对boundary加一些功能
To do this the boundary needs
我们需要先建一个
a script attached.
boundary的脚本文件
So with Boundary selected click on Add Component.
先选定Boundary然后点击Add Component
Then select New Script.
再点选New Script
Rename the script DestroyByBoundary.
将脚本文件重命名DestroyByBoundary
Accept these changes to add this script
点选确定把脚本文件添加到
to Boundary.
Boundary
Select Assets to see our new script
选Assets文件夹察看我们的新脚本
in the root level of our project.
脚本应该在项目的根目录层级下
And let's file it in the Scripts folder.
我们把它移动到Scripts文件夹
Open the Scripts folder and select
打开Scripts文件夹
DestroyByBoundary and open it for editing.
打开DestroyByBoundary脚本开始编辑
Our boundary game objects behaviour
boundary这个游戏对象
will be driven by the box collider
是由盒子形碰撞检测机驱动的
and that box collider is a trigger.
盒子形碰撞检测机是一个触发器
To find out how to script to a trigger collider
我们可以在文档中
we can search Trigger
搜索Trigger关键字来学习
in the documentation.
如何编写碰撞检测机的触发器
This will give us a list of all of the uses of
我们看到Unity's API中关于Trigger(触发器)
Trigger in Unity's API/
的内容的列表
We want to destroy the shots as they
我们需要把子弹在它离开
leave the box collider's trigger volume.
盒子碰撞检测机的触发器时销毁子弹
So let's look at OnTriggerExit.
所以我们看一下OnTriggerExit这个函数
If we look at the description it tells us that
我们看一下这个函数的介绍
OnTriggerExit is called when the other
OnTriggerExit是在其他碰撞检测机
collider has stopped touching the trigger.
离开触发器的时候被调用的
Conveniently the sample code does
示例代码正好是
exactly what we want.
我们要做的事情
When the other collider leaves the
当其他的碰撞检测机
Boundary's trigger volume
离开Boundary这个触发器的时候
we want to destroy the other
我们需要销毁
collider's game object.
那个游戏对象
Copy this code and paste it in to our script.
把这个代码复制粘贴到我们的脚本当中
Save this script and return to Unity.
保存脚本回到Unity
When we select Boundary we don't see any
当我们选择Boundary后
properties on the component.
我们看不到任何脚本相关的组建的属性
This is because there are no options
这是因为这个组件
we can set on this component.
没有任何需要设定的选项
This component simply does it's job
这个组件只单纯做它的本职工作
if it's active, destroying any object that
在激活状态下,消除一切离开
leave the trigger's volume.
触发器的对象
Now that our boundary is setup and in position
现在我们的boundary设定好了
we can remove the mesh renderer
让我们把网格渲染器
and the mesh filter components.
和网格过滤器的组件都删掉
Let's save the scene and test.
让我们保存一下场景测试一下
And as the shots leave the game area
当子弹离开游戏区域的时候
they are destroyed.
子弹消失了
With our ship setup and it's weapons systems
我们的飞船和武器都设定好了
ready to go, in the next assignment we will
下一个任务是给我们的玩家制造新的挑战
create hazards to challenge our player.
小行星来袭